Vodou religious expression in Haiti collected by Odette Mennesson Rigaud, Milo Rigaud, and Shirley Keller
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 3: Various sound recordings
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR056; WIRE 01088; 1 sound wire reel: analog
    Written on the wire spool: abime' pas bousee courant attention reste 1/4 [?] [other details, not transcribed]
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR057; WIRE 01089; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:30:00): analog
    Box panel: Vierge [?] 17 + 5 + 8 / Titon (etudes)
    Written on the wire spool: Vierge [?] 170 + 5 + 8
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR058; WIRE 01090; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel: passé / 44' / Bandes (1-) e[?] 5' / Bandes (2) tressé rubaus 12' / Bande roi diab' 10' / Bande mascaron (2) / Bande Roi diab' / Bande Silvestre danse Rois / Bande Cholo danse Rois / Bande vaccines / Bande Rori Tuba - inter calée / Bandes 44'
    Written on the wire spool: Bande Petronelle / env. [?] 45'
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR059; WIRE 01091; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel: Ti Jazz avec Titon / 60' [??]
    Written on the wire spool: Ti Jazz avec Titon
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR060; WIRE 01092; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog, 7 1/2 ips
    Box panel: Meringues - Julia / avec [?] / 1. Belle Congo 3 / 2. Tip' pa com [?] 2 / 3. Carle ca'que o similar 2 / Meringues / Julia / 7 1/2 [ips]
    Written on the wire spool: Meringues / Julia / 7 1/2 [ips] / [?]
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR071; WIRE 01103; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:30:00): analog; Possibly a blank wire ("made erased")
    Box panel: passé effacér
    Written on the wire spool: passé
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR072; WIRE 01104; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:30:00): analog
    Box panel: a passer
    Written on the wire spool: a passer 1#
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR073; WIRE 01105; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:15:00): analog
    Box panel: effacer 30' / Grade I / a S[?]der
    Written on the wire spool: 30' effacé [?]
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR074; WIRE 01106; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel: rerecording - V / 3 Zaca Titon - Julia [further details on the box panel]
    Box lid: Rerecording V / Tape 5
    Written on the wire spool: passé / Rerecording V / x Titon 8'
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR075; WIRE 01107; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel: a effacer I
    Written on the wire spool: passé vierge [?] mo[?]s 10'
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR076; WIRE 01108; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:30:00): analog; This wire was received without an original container.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR077; WIRE 01109; 1 sound wire reel (unknown duration): analog; This wire was received without an original container; it was packed in a plastic bag. The wire is partially sprung.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR078; WIRE 01110; 1 sound wire reel: analog; This wire was received without an original container; it was packed in a plastic bag. The wire is partially sprung.
  - Sound recording, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR079; WIRE 01111; 1 sound wire reel: analog; This wire was received without an original container; it was packed in a plastic bag. Wire wrapped around a paper roll of register or calculator tape. The recording is probably 30 minutes or less in length.
  - Spoken translation of a letter from French to English, June 30, 1983, The file content of relevance is sound only. The video shows a desk, where the recording equipment sat during the recording.
    The audio content begins about 00:00:06. Nina (otherwise unidentified) reads an English translation of a letter (originally written in French by Odette Rigaud) to Shirley Keller. In the letter Rigaud writes about her current health and domestic circumstances. Shirley Keller is the woman listening (and occasionally speaking in response). The original letter, translated after 2001, was dictated by Rigaud to Marie (otherwise unidentified).
    - DVD carrier for DC001, AFC 2019/041: DC001; 1 DVD-R (Box-folder 1/2)
      See afc2019041_dc001_aip_01 for the digital file.
    - Digital content on DC001, afc2019041_dc001_aip_01; 1 VOB file (172 MB; 00:05:58): digital, sound, color
      Digital copy of DVD extracted from original by AFC staff for preservation and access purposes.
  - Sound recording, circa 1972-1974, circa 1972-19674; AFC 2019/041: SR080; RXK 4064; 1 sound reel (polyester, 00:32:05): analog, 3 3/4 ips; half track, stereo; 7 in.; The tape is an incomplete aircheck from an unspecified New York/New Jersey radio station (going by the included commercials) that has nothing to do with Haiti. It is an audio documentary about the early days of The Rolling Stones. The documentary is British in origin and features interviews with people not normally heard from in retrospectives.
    Documentary on the Rolling Stones (musical group). While the content is out of scope for the collection, this recording has been retained.
    Written on the tape reel flange: Stones Story 14, 45, 81, 101, 150, 170
- Series 4: Dubbed commercial recordings
  - African discs, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR061; WIRE 01093; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel: Afrique - copie disques V. / 60'
    Box lid: Afrique - copie disques V. / 60'
    Written on the wire spool: Afrique disques V.
    African disc copies
  - African discs, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR062; WIRE 01094; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:30:00): analog
    Box panel: Congo belge 30' / chants et danses / Afrique copie disques
    Written on the wire spool: Congo belge 30' / chants et danses
    Accompanying documentation: African disc copies
  - Classical music, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR082; WIRE 01112; 1 sound wire reel: analog; It is assumed this spool contains disc copies; this is to be confirmed.
    Box panel: Andano etude (Mendelssohn) / Rondo brillant (Weber)
    Written on the wire spool: Tagliafero [further details on the spool]
    Accompanying documentation: Classical music
  - Flamenco discs, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR063; WIRE 01095; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:30:00): analog
    Box panel: Flamenco - copie disques V. / Flamenco - copie disques Valentine [?]
    Written on the wire spool: Flamenco (disques V.)
    Accompanying documentation: Flamenco disc copies
  - Haitian discs, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR064; WIRE 01096; 1 sound wire reel (approx. 00:23:00): analog
    Box panel: [??] disques haitiens
    Written on the wire spool: [?] 23'
    Accompanying documentation: Haitian disc copies
  - Jazz discs, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR065; WIRE 01097; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:15:00): analog
    Box panel: Jazz copie disques V.
    Box lid: Jazz copie disques V.
    Written on the wire spool: pas bon Jazz copie disques V. / 1/2 minute free
  - Jazz discs, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR066; WIRE 01098; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:25:00): analog
    Box panel: Duke Ellington - Liberian Suite / Liberian Suite - Duke Ellington [?] 25'
    Written on the wire spool: Liberian Suite [?]. 25'
    Accompanying documentation: Jazz disc copies
  - Jazz discs, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR067; WIRE 01099; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel: copie disque V. 8' / Jazz copie disques V. 8'
    Written on the wire spool: copie disques V. Jazz 28'
  - Jazz discs, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR068; WIRE 01100; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 01:00:00): analog
    Box panel: Jazz copie disques V. / attentian [?] casse / Jazz copie disques V. / Casse ce [?] plus [?] places
    Written on the wire spool: essais toto
  - South American discs, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR069; WIRE 01101; 1 sound wire reel (Webster-Chicago, approx. 00:15:00): analog
    Box panel: Musique Sud Americaine / copie disques V. / Sud Americaine / copie disques V.
    Written on the wire spool: Argentina samba etc [?] copie disques / Roger
    Accompanying documentation: South American disc copies
  - Various discs, undated, AFC 2019/041: SR070; WIRE 01102; 1 sound wire reel (unknown duration): analog
    Box panel: 2/2 Peeter [Peter] - Marlene Dietrich /2/2 Johnny [Jonny] - Marlene Dietrich /2/2 Kasbek - Igor Gorin /2/2 Viut viteé [Viut Vitre] ([?]) - Igor Gorin /2/2 Song of the Plains - Red Army Choir /2/2 Write What [?] - Red Army Choir /5 The moon shine (danse [?]) /2/2 Saetas - Niña de los Peines / Bulerias [?] - Niña de los Peines / Tango flamenco - Niña de los Peines / Sevillanas - Niña de los Peines
    Box lid: Dietrich Russian-Flamenco
    Written on the wire spool: Dietrich II - Russian Flamenco
    Accompanying documentation: various disc copies